Lovin，欢迎你们这些漂亮的人来看第二部分。
Lovin you beautiful people are welcome to part two.
导航Linux文件系统。
Navigating the Linux file system.
因此，在这段视频中，我们将在上一段视频中了解到的有关使用PWT的知识的基础上再接再厉
So in this video we're going to build upon what we learned in the last video about using the PWT and
LS命令。
the LS commands.
但在本视频中，您将了解如何使用cd命令在文件系统中实际移动。
But in this video you're going to learn how to use the cd command to actually move around the file system.
您将学习绝对路径和相对路径之间的区别。
You're going to learn the difference between absolute and relative paths.
您可以了解一些非常棒的键盘快捷键，这些快捷键将使文件系统导航变得如此快速
You can learn some awesome keyboard shortcuts that will make navigating the file system so quick and
非常简单，基本上您将看到如何将pwt、ls和cd命令组合在一起，以
so easy and you basically going to see how you can put together the PWT the Ls and the CD commands to
优雅地导航文件系统。
elegantly navigate the file system.
在本视频结束时，您将了解有关导航Linux所需了解的一切
By the end of this video you're going to know everything you need to know about navigating the Linux
使用命令行的文件系统，您稍加练习就会发现，您很快就会同意我的观点
file system using the command line and you watch with a bit of practice you'll soon agree with me that
这样做比使用点击式图形方法要快得多，效率也高得多
doing it this way is a lot faster and a lot more effective than using your pointy clicky graphical methods
你一直在用的东西。
that you've been using.
到目前为止可能是你一生中的全部。
Probably all of your life so far.
那么让我们直接跳到你的超级英雄训练的下一部分吧。
So let's go ahead and jump right into this next part of your superhero training.
好的。
OK.
在上一个视频中，我们看到可以使用P W D命令来查看我们在文件系统上的位置
So in the last video we saw that we could use the P W D command to see where we were on the file system
我们看到，我们可以将ls命令与各种不同的选项一起使用，基本上可以四处查看
and we saw that we could use the ls command with a variety of different options to basically look around
并列出进入时目录中的内容。
and list what was in the directory the way in.
但是仅使用这两个命令，我们就有点停留在一个地方，如何才能真正移动
But using just these two commands we're kind of stuck in the one place right how can we actually move
从我们的主目录。
from our home directory.
好的，缺少的部分是CD命令，而CD命令代表更改目录。
Well the missing piece is the C D command and the cd command stands for change directory.
假设我们使用的是最后一个类型，我们注意到Downloads文件夹位于
So let's say that we used our last kind and we saw that the downloads folder by noting that it's in
蓝色，这是一个文件夹，我们想进入Downloads文件夹。
blue and it's a folder and we wanted to go into the downloads folder.
我们怎么才能做到这一点。
How would we do that.
我们可以用几种方式做到这一点。
What we could do it in a few ways.
首先，我们可以为cd命令提供我们想要到达的位置的绝对路径，从
Firstly we can give the cd command the absolute path for where we want to go with a go starting at the
基本目录，我们去劈开，然后回家，然后Ziyad下载，好的，我们可以像这样键入
base directory we'd go slash then home then Ziyad then downloads OK and we could type that in like that
这完全可以工作，或者如果我们不想将整个路径写入我们的主目录
and that would totally work or if we didn't want to have to write the entire path to our home directory
我们可以把这一切都换成蒂尔达。
we could just replace all that with the Tilda.
我们说OK，转到我们的主目录，然后下载，这就是您可以通过快捷方式使用波浪号的地方
We say OK go change to our home directory and then download that's where you'd use the tilde at a shortcut
或者我们可以使用的是所谓的相对路径号相对路径是相对于的路径
or what we could use is something known as a relative path number relative path is a path relative to
你现在的位置。
where you currently are.
好的，因为我们当前在主文件夹中，如何才能到达Downloads文件夹。
OK so because we're currently in the home folder how do we get to the downloads folder.
好的，如果我们打开图形图形菜单，让我们想一想。
Well let's think about it if we open up the graphical graphical menu.
我们在这里，我们在主文件夹中，从这里开始。
Here we are we're in the home folder from here.
我们要怎么做才能进入Downloads文件夹。
What do we do to get to the downloads folder.
我们真正要做的就是点击正确的下载，这样你就可以说那是一个亲戚
We literally all we have to do is just click downloads right so that you can say that that's a relative
从这里到下载的路径，这就是我们要做的全部工作。
path which is going from here to the download that's all we've got to do.
因此，要切换到Downloads文件夹，我们所要做的就是键入Downloads。
So to change to the downloads folder all we've got to do is type downloads.
如果我们这样做，如果我们只键入cd，然后像这样下载，然后按Enter键，您就可以看到
So if we do that if we just type CD and then downloads just like that and press ENTER you can see that
我们更改了目录，shell提示符也发生了更改，之前它只是Tilda告诉我们的
we have changed directory and a shell prompt has changed as well before it was just the tilda telling
我们在我们的主目录中。
us that we were in our home directory.
现在，它显示我们位于主目录和内部的Downloads文件夹中。
Now it's saying we're in our home directory and the downloads folder inside.
好的。
OK.
如果我们使用pwt命令，这里的蓝色文本显示了我们当前所在位置的路径
So this is this text in blue here shows us the path to where we currently on if we use the PWT command
现在我们可以看到，我们可以在劈开主页获得SLASY或劈开下载，我们还可以通过按下
now we can see that we get slash home slashy or slash downloads and we can also look around by pressing
ls命令，我们可以看到该文件夹中实际上什么都没有。
the ls command and we can see that there's actually nothing inside that folder.
好的，所以都不是，我们不是下载文件夹。
OK so neither We're not Downloads folder.
这是给你的一个挑战。
Here's a challenge for you.
继续发布视频，看看是否可以使用cd命令切换回我们的主目录。
Go ahead and post the video and see if you can use the CD command to change back to our home directory.
因此，请继续暂停视频，尝试一下，然后再回来看看您做得如何。
So go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot and then come back to see how you did.
你成功了吗。
Did you manage it.
如果是这样的话真的真的做得很好。
If so really really well done.
您现在学得非常快，您可以使用这样的绝对路径来完成它，您可以输入cd
You learn super quickly now you could have done it using an absolute path like this you could type CD
然后是劈开，主页劈开，你的用户名，或者其他任何东西，在我的例子中，它是兹亚德劈开。
then slash home slash your username or whatever would be in my case it Ziyad slash.
就这样了。
And that's it.
好的，这样就可以了。
OK that would work.
或者你可以用一辆蒂尔达，让它变得又好又简单，只需用CD，然后用阿提拉。
Or you could have used a Tilda to make it nice and easy just use CD and then Attilla.
现在我有点作弊，因为你可以用另一种方式来做这件事。
Now I kind of cheated a little bit because there's another way that you could have done it.
从现在开始，这可能就是你做这件事的方式。
And this is the way you probably do it from now on.
但我以前没给你看过这个。
But I haven't shown you this before.
现在，默认情况下，如果您不给我任何输入，cd命令会将您带到您的主文件夹。
Now by default if you don't give me any input the CD command will take you to your home folder.
因此，如果我们只需从头开始输入cd，输入cd并按Enter键，您只需查看shell即可看到
So if we just type CD like from scratch type CD and press ENTER you can see by just looking at the shell
提示我们已返回主目录，我们可以使用Peter Beattie进行确认。
prompt that we've ended up back in our home directory we can use Peter Beattie to confirm that.
我的意思是，它告诉我们，我们回到了主目录，无论我之前在哪里，这都会起作用
I mean it tells us that we are back in our home directory and that will work no matter where I was previously
在文件系统上，我可能在文件系统的任何位置，所有的DO都是键入cd或按Enter键
on the file system I could have been anywhere on the file system all of the do is type CD or press Enter
然后我将返回主目录。
then I will end up back in the home directory.
很酷，对吧。
Pretty cool right.
好的很好。
Okay great.
现在我们回到主文件夹，我想向您展示ls命令的一个非常有用的选项。
So now we're back in the home folder I want to show you a very useful option for the ls command.
这有点像戴着X光眼镜。
It's kind of like wearing X-ray glasses.
这是一个A选项，这个选项对所有人来说都是短的。
And it's the A option that the option is short for all.
它还允许您查看目录中的所有文件，甚至包括隐藏的文件。
And it allows you to see all of the files in a directory even the hidden files.
所以如果我输入ls并给它一个选项OK。
So if I type ls and give it the option OK.
如果我按Enter键，您会注意到我们在这里看到了很多东西。
If I press Enter you'll notice that we see a whole lot of stuff in here.
把它打印出来。
Print it out.
好的，如果我清除顶部的屏幕，只显示最后一个选项，然后显示带有A选项的ls
OK if I clear the screen on top you just the last option and then show you the ls with the A option
你会看到我们用A选项得到了更多的东西。
you'll see we get a lot more stuff with the A option.
现在，您会注意到很多这样的文件都有以点开头的秋季名称，这意味着
Now a lot of these files you'll notice have fall names beginning with dots and that means that there
隐藏文件，甚至隐藏目录。
hidden files or even hidden directories.
好的。
OK.
现在，如果我们在图形编辑器中查看，默认情况下可能无法实际看到它们，但是如果我们
Now if we look in the graphical editor we may not be able to actually see them by default but if we
像我们在上几个视频中所做的那样，单击此处并显示隐藏文件，我们现在也可以看到它们
click up here like we do in the last few videos and show hidden files we can now see them as well so
您可以看到，我们得到的输出完全相同，这就是您显示隐藏文件的方式
you look you can see that we're getting exactly the same output so that's how you show hidden files
使用使用ls命令。
using the using the the the ls command.
好的。
OK.
您可能还注意到，我们在这里有我们在几个视频之前制作的bash别名文件。
And you may also notice in here that we've got our bash alias's file that we made a few videos ago.
我之所以提到这一点，是因为每个文件夹中有两个非常重要的隐藏文件夹。
Now the reason I mention this is because these two very important hidden folders inside each folder.
它们是点文件夹和双点文件夹。
They are the dot and the double dot folders.
好的。
OK.
现在，这些快捷方式可以让您更轻松地移动或引用整个文件系统上的内容
Now these are shortcuts to allow you to move around easier or refer to stuff on your file system a whole
容易多了。
lot easier.
doc文件夹只是指当前目录。
The doc folder simply refers to the current directory.
好的。
OK.
例如，如果我转到Desktop文件夹，OK，我们就可以打印了。
So for example if I go to the Desktop folder OK then we can print.
很抱歉，如果我可以打印工作目录，我们可以看到我们在桌面上
My apologies if I can do print working directory and we can see that we have that we are in the desktop
如果我们的列表包含内容，那么我的桌面上应该不会有任何内容。
and if our list its contents this shouldn't really be anything on my desktop.
但始终存在此数据文件夹和双点文件夹，它们仅在使用ls和选项时才可见
But there always is this data and double dot folders which are only visible using the ls with the option
正常地址的地址。
of just the normal address.
决斗选手DASH 8不会出现。
It doesn't show up for duellists dash 8.
他们出现了。
They show up.
好的。
OK.
现在我们在这里有圆点和双点文件夹。
Now in here we've got the dot and the double dot folders.
如果我尝试对doc文件夹执行cd操作，Bash基本上会停留在shell将停留的位置
If I try to do cd to the doc folder Bash is basically going to stay where is the shell is going to stay
如果我这么做的话具体在哪里。
exactly where is if I do that.
您可以看到，我们仍然在桌面上查看shell提示符，因为DOT文件夹引用了
You can see that we're still in the desktop looking at the shell prompt because the DOT folder refers
到我们当前所在的文件夹。
to the current folder that we're in.
好的。
OK.
这只是这个文件夹的一种说法。
It's just a way of saying this folder.
好的。
OK.
现在如果我去打双打怎么样？
Now what if I went to the doubleback.
如果我做CD翻倍怎么样？好的。
What if I do cd doubled up OK.
您注意到我们确实进行了更改，并且实际上回到了我们的主文件夹Double Up文件夹中
You noticed that we did actually change and were in fact back in our home folder the doubled up folder
指的是父文件夹或我们当前所在的上面的文件夹。
means the parent folder or the folder above where we currently are.
好的。
OK.
如果我回到桌面，你可以看到，如果我按下CD，我们就会有翻倍的东西，翻倍
So if I go back to the desktop you can see that we've got the doubled up for if I press CD double that
我们又回到了一个文件夹里。
we've gone back up a folder.
这会将我们带到主目录，以防我们回到主目录，让我们清除屏幕。
Which brings us into the home directory in case we're back in a home directory let's clear the screen.
如果我继续走下去。
What if I kept going.
好的，如果我看到点，我现在在实际的主文件夹中，它不是我的主文件夹，而是
OK if I go see the dot dot I'm now in the actual home folder which is not my home folder but it's the
位于我的主文件夹上方的文件夹。
folder above my home folder.
好的，我们继续走吧。
OK let's keep going.
请看圆点。
See the dot dot.
现在我们实际上只是在劈开中，我们在整个系统的基本目录中。
And now we're actually just in the slash for the we're in the base directory for the whole system.
好的。
OK.
看看还能不能再高一点，我们去C.D.点。
See if we can go any higher we go C.D dot dot.
你可以看到我们不能再往上走了，因为雪泥文件夹里的灰尘是
You can see that we can't go any higher because the dust the slush folder is the highest point on the
文件系统。
file system.
好的。
OK.
如果我做一个基本目录中的内容，我们可以看一下周围的情况。
And we can actually have a look around if I do an ls what's in the base directory.
看，这里有相当多的文件，当我们有一些文件的下一步信息时，你会看到这些文件
See there's quite a lot of files here that you saw when we had a little bit of next mation of the file
系统中有bin文件夹、boot文件夹、ETSI文件夹，其中包含您的配置
system you've got the bin folder the boot folder the folder the ETSI folder which is full of your configuration
文件。
files.
主文件夹，这是我们刚要去取我们的家居用品的地方。
The home folder which is where we just were to get our home stuff.
图书馆的媒体，也就是你拥有房间的地方，移走衣柜里的你可选的东西。
The library's media which is where you have your room remove wardrobe's your optional stuff.
路由用户主文件夹等。
The route users home folder and so on.
关于变量文件、临时文件、用户内容等等，我猜这些是文件夹和
So on the variable files temp files user stuff and so on and so on I guess these are the folders and
不管怎么说，其中最重要的是我给你的小抄，我们谈到的那些
the most important of these anyway are the ones that I gave you a cheat sheet where we talked about
文件系统。
the file system.
好的。
OK.
看看会发生什么。
And see what happens.
这是root用户的主文件夹。
This is the root user's home folder right.
这是管理员的主文件夹。
This is the home folder for the administrator.
让我们试着看看如果我们试图进入它会发生什么。
Let's try and see what happens if we try to enter it.
如果我们确实看到路线OK并按Enter，您可以看到我们得到的许可被拒绝。
If we do see the route OK and press enter you can see that we get permission denied.
好的，这里有一些你被允许进入的文件夹和一些你不被允许进入的文件夹。
OK so there's some folders that you were allowed into and some folders that you're not allowed into.
因此，我们没有足够的权限来访问root用户的主目录。
So we don't have enough privileges to be able to access the root user's home directory.
嗯，试试看ETSI文件夹和配置文件怎么样？
Well what about the ETSI folder OK along with the configuration files as try that.
如果我们试一试CD，看看我们怎样才能进入那张CD，让我们看看里面有什么。
If we try CD and see how we can get into that one let's see what's in there for us.
告诉我们你能看到里面所有的东西，对吧。
Ls us who you can see the whole bunch of stuff in there right.
你在这里放了一些文件夹。
And you get some folders in here.
蓝色的或文件夹和白色的文件，有些也有不同的类型。
The blue ones or folders and the white ones files and some of them have different types as well.
但你不必担心这一点。
But you don't have to worry about that.
大多数情况下，你会看到蓝色和白色，蓝色的文件夹，白色的文件，你可以输入任何东西
Mostly what you'll see are blue and white blue ones folders white one files and you can enter anything
你想要的东西。
that you want in there.
例如，这里有一个，我们在哪里找呢。
For example there's one here where are we looking.
这里有一个叫DHC Pay的，我们可以进入那个文件夹。
There's one here called DHC pay we could go into that folder.
我们可以试试CD DHC页面。
We could try CD DHC page.
好的。
OK.
现在看看里面有什么。
Now what's in there.
我们可以做l，我们可以四处看看，我们可以在那里看到其他的东西。
We could do ls and we can have a look around we can see this other stuff in there.
那边还有一个。
There's another one there.
De D.H.爬了上去，并到了钩天。
De D.H. climbed and to hook day.
我们试着把DH客户的仪表盘和仪表盘挂钩。
Let's try to get the D.H. client dash and dash hooks.
你可以看到我们在那里，那里有两个L，我们在那里看到了其他的东西。
You can see that we're in there what's in there two Ls we see this other stuff in there.
这里的绿色是程序，但是您可以在这里看到我们在文件中移动的方式
The green ones here are programs but you can see here right the way that we are moving around the file
系统使用CD来移动LS来查看我们周围的情况，或者使用Peter Beattie来确认确切的位置
system using either CD to move LS to see what's around us or Peter Beattie to confirm exactly where
我们是。
we are.
就是这样，你实际上会在整个系统中移动，而且它不会改变
And it's this way that you will actually move around the entire system and it doesn't change no matter
您所在的位置只要您有权限输入这些文件夹，您只需使用以下命令即可进入这些文件夹
where you are as long as you've got the permissions to enter those folders you can get there using just
cd命令，您可以使用ls命令四处查看，并且可以确认您正在使用的位置
the cd command and you can look around using the ls command and you can confirm where you are using
PIDO EDI命令。
the Pido EDI command.
现在我们怎么才能一直回到我们的主文件夹。
Now how do we get all the way back to our home folder.
非常简单，只需按cd按Enter，我们就会回到主文件夹。
Very easy just press CD press enter and we are back in our home folder.
因此，您可以在Linux文件系统中的任何位置看到您需要做的几乎任何事情
So you can see the pretty much anything that you need to do in the Linux file system anywhere in the
只要您对CD拥有所需的权限，就可以移动到您想要移动到的扩展。
expansion that you want to move to as long as you have the required permissions on the CD.
LS和Peter真的很有号召力，你可以去任何你想去的地方，如果你迷路了，或者穿上了Pido的鞋子
LS And Peter really commands and you can get wherever you want and if you get lost or shoes the Pido
E-D命令检查你在哪里相当史诗吧。
E-D command to check where you are pretty epic right.
现在我们回到了主文件夹，我想教你们最后一件事。
So now that we're back in our home folder there's one final thing that I want to teach you.
这就是所谓的制表符补全。
And that's called tab completion.
但是看在上帝的份上，以及我们在过去几个视频中学到的所有东西的总结，我会再来看你的
But for goodness as well as a summary of everything we've learned in the past few videos I'll see you
在下一个视频中。
in the next video.